When a group of Australians was asked why they believed climate change was not happening, about 36% said it was “common sense”, according to a report published last year by the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation.
根据澳大利亚联邦科学与工业研究组织去年发布的一份报告，一群澳大利亚人被问及为何认为气候变化没有发生时，约36%的人说这是“常识”。
This was the most popular reason for their opinion, with only 11% saying their belief that climate change was not happening was based on scientific research.
这是他们持这种观点最常见的理由，而只有11%的人说，他们认为气候变化没有发生，是以科学研究为依据的。
But what do we mean by an appeal to common sense?
但我们说诉诸常识，指的是什么呢？
Presumably it’s an appeal to rationality of some sort that forms the basis of more complex reasoning.
这大概是诉诸某种理性，而这种理性构成了更复杂推理的基础。
The appeal to common sense, however, is usually nothing more than an appeal to thinking that just feels right, but what feels right to one person may not feel right to another.
然而，诉诸常识通常不过是诉诸那些只是感觉对的想法，而一个人觉得对的，另一个人未必觉得对。
Whether it feels right is usually a reflection of the world view and ideologies we have internalised, and that frames how we interact with new ideas.
感觉对不对，通常反映的是我们已经内化的世界观和意识形态，而这又框定了我们对待新观念的方式。
When new ideas are in accord with what we already believe, they are more readily accepted.
新观念与我们原本就相信的东西相符时，更容易被人接受。
When they are not, they, and the arguments that lead to them, are more readily rejected.
如果不相符，这些观念以及推导出它们的论证，就更容易遭到拒斥。
We often mistake this automatic compatibility testing of new ideas with existing beliefs for an application of common sense, but, in reality, it is more about judging than thinking.
我们常常把这种自动检验新观念与已有信念是否相容的做法，误当作是在运用常识，但实际上，这更多是在评判，而不是在思考。
As Nobelist Daniel Kahneman notes in Thinking, Fast and Slow, when we arrive at conclusions in this way, the outcomes also feel true, regardless of whether they are.
正如诺贝尔奖得主丹尼尔·卡尼曼在《思考，快与慢》一书中所指出的，我们以这种方式得出结论时，结果同样会让人感觉是真的，不管实际上是否为真。
We are not psychologically well equipped to judge our own thinking.
从心理上说，我们并不具备充分的能力来评判自己的思维。
We are also highly susceptible to a range of cognitive biases such as giving preference to the first things that come to mind when making decisions or giving weight to evidence.
我们还极易受到一系列认知偏差的影响，比如在做决定或权衡证据时，偏向最先想到的东西。
One way we can check our internal biases and inconsistencies is through the social verification of knowledge, in which we test our ideas in a rigorous and systematic way to see if they make sense not just to us, but to other people.
我们要检查自身内在的偏差和不一致之处，一种方法是借助知识的社会验证，即以严谨、系统的方式检验我们的想法，看它们是否不仅对我们自己说得通，对其他人也说得通。
The outstanding example of this socially shared cognition is science.
科学就是这种社会共享认知最突出的范例。
That does not mean that individuals are not capable of excellent thinking, nor does it mean no individual is rational.
这并不意味着个人没有能力出色地思考，也不意味着没有哪个人是理性的。
But the extent to which individuals can do this on their own is a function of how well integrated they are with communities of systematic inquiry in the first place.
但个人能在多大程度上独立做到这一点，取决于他们原本在多大程度上融入了从事系统探究的群体。
You can’t learn to think well by yourself.
你无法独自学会好好思考。
In matters of science at least, those who value their common sense over methodological, collaborative investigation imagine themselves to be more free in their thinking, unbound by involvement with the group, but in reality they are tightly bound by their capabilities and perspectives.
至少在科学问题上，那些把自己的常识看得比讲求方法的协作研究更重要的人，自以为思维更加自由，不会因参与到群体之中而受到束缚；但实际上，他们被自身的能力和视角紧紧束缚着。
We are smarter together than we are individually, and perhaps that’s just common sense.
我们在一起比各自单独时更聪明，或许这本来就是常识。